Neel Shah

https://neelshah18.github.io

SUMMARY

Experienced interdisciplinary researcher in health and customer analysis. My academic and extracurricular pursuits have developed a solid knowledge base in data analysis, machine learning, programming languages and scientific programming applications for large scale system design. Recent graduate with my second Master's degree and second publication.

Technical Skills

- Languages: Python, R, Java, C, C++
- Technologies: AWS, Linux server, Rest API, Flask, Tornado
- Database: MongoDB, Elasticsearch, MySQL, Redis
- Machine/Deep Learning: Regression Models, Tree Models, Clustering Models, SVM, CNN, RNN, Gradient models, LSTM

Experience

• Data Analysis Research Assistant

Thudner bay, ON

datalab.science

November 2017 - May 2019

Email: neelshah181993@gmail.com

Mobile: +1-807-356-5415

- o Successfully implemented real-time health analysis system for Canada using social media data with 93% multiclass classification using Random forest.
- o Designed and developed LSTM model for analysing and predicting diabetic trend in Canada through social media data on distributed NVIDIA Titan-X CUDA server using tensorflow.
- o Created largest open source food database "Food in one" with 333K data points.
- o Designed and developed "Elasticsearch" on distributed server with 20 nodes which allow searching from 330M tweets/second.
- Performed quantitative analysis of social media data for health analyzation.
- o Created data analysis pipeline and data scraper for the data of Social Media.

• Machine Learning Engineer

San Diego, CA

Datalog.ai

January 2017 - August 2017

- Developed backend NER functionality for NLP algorithm used in chatbots.
- Design and developed clustering algorithm for decision making based on chat.
- Successfully implemented 5+ visualization dashboard for backend analysis of chatbot data: semantic analysis, topic extractor & other.
- Implement asynchronous API for chatbot analysis system, which is capable of handling thousands request per second.

• Data Analysis Intern

Godhra, GJ

Panchamrut Dairy

July 2016 - December 2016

- Designed and developed a real time data analysis system for raw product cost and product transportation using python, pandas and numpy.
- Forecasted sales pattern of ice-cream using time-series with 71% efficiency.
- Performed cost analysis and report generation to reduce production cost by 1.2%.

EDUCATION

• Lakehead University

Master of Science in Computer Science; GPA: 4.00

September 2017 - May 2019

Thunder Bay, ON

• Gujarat Technology University

Master of Engineering in Information Technology; CGPA: 8.78/10

Vadodara, India August 2014 - June 2016

Gujarat Technology University

Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics; CGPA: 7.31/10

Vadodara, India

August 2010 - July 2014

OPEN SOURCE & PROJECTS

- **Emot**: Widely use open source python library(9k+ Downloads) to extract the emojis and emoticons from a text with their respective meaning.
- Sentencelab: Open source python library for text data cleaning, sentiment analysis and topic extraction.
- Bug solving and test cases: Solved more than 13 bugs and 10 test model for different open source libraries.

Funding

• Research grant: 7000\$/Yearly NSERC Discovery Grant.

Publication

- Neel Shah, Darryl Willick, and Vijay Mago. A framework for social media data analytics using elasticsearch and kibana. Wireless Networks, pages 1–9
- Neel Shah and Vijay Mago. Canadian's health analysis through social media. Data Science, IEEE (submitted)

References will be provided upon request.